Gerrit Smith Papers
Gerrit Smith Papers
Business and Industry; New York State; Politics, government and public administration; Activism and social reform; Anthony, Susan B. (Susan Brownell), 1820-1906.; Astor, John Jacob, 1763-1848.; Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887.; Blackwell, Antoinette Louisa Brown, 1825-1921.; Calkins, Caleb.; Child, Lydia Maria, 1802-1880.; Clay, Cassius Marcellus, 1810-1903.; Conkling, Alfred, 1789-1874.; Conkling, Roscoe, 1829-1888.; Dana, Charles A. (Charles Anderson), 1819-1897.; Davis, Paulina W. (Paulina Wright), 1813-1876.; Delavan, Edward C. (Edward Cornelius), 1793-1871.; Douglass, Frederick, 1818-1895.; Finney, Charles G., 1792-1875.; Foster, Abby Kelley, 1811-1887.; Garnet, Henry Highland, 1815-1882.; Garrison, William Lloyd, 1805-1879.; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872.; Green, Beriah, 1795-1874.; Grimké, Angelina Emily, 1805-1879.; Grimké, Sarah Moore, 1792-1873.; Helper, Hinton Rowan, 1829-1909.; Howe, Julia Ward, 1819-1910.; Howe, S. G. (Samuel Gridley), 1801-1876.; Littlejohn, De Witt Clinton, 1818-1892.; Mann, Horace, 1796-1859.; May, Samuel J. (Samuel Joseph), 1797-1871.; Noyes, John Humphrey, 1811-1886.; Peabody, Elizabeth Palmer, 1804-1894.; Pierpont, John, 1785-1866.; Pillsbury, Parker, 1809-1898.; Ray, Charles B.; Schoolcraft, Henry Rowe, 1793-1864.; Schoolcraft, Henry Rowe, Mrs.; Seward, William H. (William Henry), 1801-1872.; Smith, Elizabeth Oakes Prince, 1806-1893.; Smith, Gerrit, 1797-1874.; Smith, James McCune, 1813-1865.; Stanton, Elizabeth Cady, 1815-1902.; Stanton, Henry B. (Henry Brewster), 1805-1887.; Stone, Lucy, 1818-1893.; Stowe, Harriet Beecher, 1811-1896.; Sumner, Charles, 1811-1874.; Tappan, Lewis, 1788-1873.; Tilton, Theodore, 1835-1907.; Truth, Sojourner, 1799-1883.; Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862.; Van Vechten, Jacob, 1788-1871.; Weed, Thurlow, 1797-1882.; Weld, Theodore Dwight, 1803-1895.; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.; Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1807-1892.; Woodhull, Victoria C. (Victoria Claflin), 1838-1927.; Liberty Party (Madison County, N.Y.); Liberty Party (U.S.: 1840-1848); Abolitionists -- United States.; Antislavery movements -- United States.; Social reformers -- United States.; Temperance.; Women -- Suffrage -- United States.; Madison County (N.Y.) -- History.; New York (State) -- History -- 1775-1865.; Peterboro (N.Y.) -- History.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; Agreements.; Bank statements.; Bonds (negotiable instruments); Broadsides (notices); Check stubs.; Correspondence.; Deeds.; Estate records.; Indentures.; Judicial records.; Land registers.; Land surveys.; Maps (documents); Pamphlets.; Sermons.; Summonses.; Warrant books.; Wills.; Abolitionists.; Social reformers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Some original documents are restricted for preservation purposes. Photocopies have been made and placed in the appropriate locations in the collection. Researchers are encouraged to use the microfilm version of the collection if at all possible.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Gerrit Smith Miller, 1928.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - General Correspondence
    - Aaron – Abell, 1835-1873 (Box 1)
    - Adams, A. – W., 1820-1874 (Box 1)
    - Addington – Alden, 1836-1874 (Box 1)
    - Alderman – Alford, 1854-1870 (Box 1)
    - AIlen, A. – K., 1844-1874 (Box 1)
    - Allen, M. – W, 1839-1873 (Box 1)
    - Allibone – Alston, 1862-1874 (Box 1)
    - Ambush – Ames, 1843-1873 (Box 1)
    - Anderman – Angel, 1839-1873 (Box 1)
    - Anthony, Susan Brownell, 1855-1892; 19 letters (Box 1)
    - Applegate – Armstrong, 1848-1874 (Box 1)
    - Arnold – Ashley, 1846-1873 (Box 1)
    - Astor, John Jacob, 1829-1843; 78 items (Box 1)
      See also Astor, William B. for later letters from the Astors
    - Astor, William B., 1843-1862; 91 items (Box 1)
      See also Astor, John Jacob. For Astor letters addressed to Peter Smith, see the
      Peter Smith Papers
      .
    - Atkins – Averill, 1838-1871 (Box 1)
    - Avery – Ayrault, 1826-1874 (Box 1)
    - Babbitt – Backus, 1837-1874 (Box 2)
    - Bacon, A. – W., 1835-1874 (Box 2)
    - Badger – Bailey, 1835-1873 (Box 2)
    - Bailey, A. – F. (Rev.), 1870-1874 (Box 2)
    - Bailey, Gamaliel, 1838-1859 (Box 2)
    - Bailey, W.H., 1866-1873 (Box 2)
    - Bailey, William Shreve, 1859-1866 (Box 2)
    - Baird – Baker, 1847-1868 (Box 2)
    - Balcom – Bales, 1835-1874 (Box 2)
    - Ball – Bannister, 1834-1874 (Box 2)
    - Baptiste – Bardwell, 1841-1873 (Box 2)
    - Barker – Barlow, 1824-1874 (Box 2)
    - Barnard – Barnes, 1845-1874 (Box 2)
    - Barnes, Albert, 1835-1870 (Box 2)
    - Barnett – Barns, 1825-1874 (Box 2)
    - Barns, Lemon, 1858-1865; includes letters to Gerrit Smith from other correspondents (Box 2)
    - Barotti, Bartlett, 1823-1874 (Box 2)
    - Bassett – Bassford, 1860-1872 (Box 2)
    - Bates, A. – M., 1835-1874 (Box 2)
    - Bateson – Bayley, 1840-1874 (Box 2)
    - Beach – Beaumond, 1819-1872 (Box 3)
    - Becker, A. – N., 1831-1874 (Box 3)
    - Beckwith, George C., 1849-1869 (Box 3)
    - Beege – Beecher, 1839-1855 (Box 3)
    - Beecher, Henry Ward, 1866-1873; 3 items (Box 3)
    - Beekman, Thomas, 1819-1862; 21 items (Box 3)
    - Beekman – Beeson, 1854-1874 (Box 3)
    - Belden – Bell, 1860-1874 (Box 3)
    - Bellows – Benedict, 1839-1873 (Box 3)
    - Bennett – Betker, 1845-1873 (Box 3)
    - Bibb – Bigelow, 1824-1874 (Box 3)
    - Binga – Birdseye, 1841-1874 (Box 3)
    - Birdseye, Ezekiel, 1841-1846 (Box 3)
    - Birney, A. – M., 1871 (Box 3)
    - Birney, David B. and M. Antoinette, 1848-1874; 3 letters (Box 3)
    - Birney, Elizabeth P. (Fitzhugh), 1850-1867; 7 letters (Box 3)
    - Birney, James, 1846-1871; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Birney, James Gillespie, 1839-1857 (Box 3)
    - Birney, William, 1843-1870; 10 letters (Box 3)
    - Bishop – Bissell, 1828-1874 (Box 3)
    - Bissell, G. – W., 1859-1881; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Black – Blackman, 1835-1870 (Box 4)
    - Blackwell, Antoinette and Louisa Brown, 1851-1869; 9 letters (Box 4)
    - Blackwell, Henry 8., 1870; 1 item (Box 4)
    - Blair – Blanchard, 1847-1874 (Box 4)
    - Blanchard, Jonathan, 1840-1874 (Box 4)
    - Bland – Bleecker, 1835-1874 (Box 4)
    - Bliss – Bloomfield, 1840-1873 (Box 4)
    - Bloomfield, Joseph E., 1856-1869; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Bloomfield, Julia, 1858-1873 (Box 4)
    - Bogart – Bond, 1859-1874 (Box 4)
    - Bonham – Booth, 1852-1873 (Box 4)
    - Borrlen – Borra, 1837-1874 (Box 4)
    - Bovee, Marvin H., 1859-1874; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Bowe – Boyd, 1845-1874 (Box 4)
    - Boyden – Boynton, 1848-1874 (Box 4)
    - Brace – Bradburn, 1859-1874 (Box 4)
    - Bradburn, George, 1845-1873; undated; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Bradford, A. – V., 1837-1874 (Box 5)
    - Bradish – Brayton, 1838-1874 (Box 5)
    - Breckinridge – Brewster, 1834-1874 (Box 5)
    - Bridge – Brittan, 1843-1874 (Box 5)
    - Brockett – Bronson, 1840-1874 (Box 5)
    - Bronson, Alvin, 1853-1870 (Box 5)
    - Brooke – Brotherson, 1847-1874 (Box 5)
    - Brown, A. – E., 1844-1872 (Box 5)
    - Brown, F. – L., 1850-1872 (Box 5)
    - Brown, M. – Z., 1831-1874 (Box 5)
    - Brown, John (Rev.) (not of Harper's Ferry), 1823-1864 (Box 5)
    - Brown, William Wells, 1862-1873; 3 letters (Box 5)
    - Browne – Brownson, 1834-1873 (Box 5)
    - Bruce – Bryant, 1828-1874 (Box 5)
    - Buchanan, Joseph Rhodes, 1848-1869 (Box 5)
    - Buchanan – Buffum, 1836-1872 (Box 5)
    - Buffum, Arnold, 1835-1840 (Box 5)
    - Bugbee – Bunner, 1831-1874 (Box 5)
    - Bunner, Catharine C., 1861-1871 (Box 5)
    - Bunner, ElÍzabeth, 1841-1869 (Box 5)
    - Burchard – Burke, 1830-1874 (Box 5)
    - Burleigh – Burns, 1837-1874 (Box 5)
    - Burnside, Ambrose, 1865 (Box 5)
    - Burr – Burns, 1849-1859 (Box 5)
    - Burrit, Elihu, 1846-1872; 14 letters and 3 items of non-correspondence (Box 5)
    - Burroughs – Bushnell, 1841-1869 (Box 5)
    - Butler – Byrdsall, 1830-1874 (Box 5)
    - Cabell – Cadwallader, 1859-1873 (Box 6)
    - Cady – Caldwell, 1841-1874 (Box 6)
    - Calhoun, James Edward, 1862-1867; 3 letters (Box 6)
    - Calkins, Caleb, 1838-1892; undated (Box 6)
    - Calkins, L.G. – Camp, 1837-1873 (Box 6)
    - Campbell, A. – M., 1837-1874 (Box 6)
    - Candee – Cardozo, 1838-1871 (Box 6)
    - Carey, Matthew, 1832-1833; 6 letters (Box 6)
    - Carmalt – Carrington, 1827-1874 (Box 6)
    - Carroll, Anna Ella, 1854-1874 (Box 6)
    - Carroll, A. – M., 1828-1474 (Box 6)
    - Carskaddan – Castle, 1845-1374 (Box 6)
    - Catlin, C. – O., 1819-1869 (Box 6)
    - Caufman – Cauley, 1852-1869 (Box 6)
    - Chaffee – Chandler, 1837-1874 (Box 6)
    - Chandler, Joseph Ripley, 1833-1861; 4 letters (Box 6)
    - Channing, William Ellery, 1839-1841; 4 letters (Box 6)
    - Channing – Chaplin, 1837-1871 (Box 6)
    - Chapman, B. – W., 1839-1874; undated (Box 6)
    - Chase, Salmon P., 1842-1846; undated; 5 letters (Box 6)
    - Chase – Chavis, 1837-1871 (Box 6)
    - Cheever, George Barrell, 1836-1870; 8 letters (Box 6)
    - Cheever, Henry, 1859-1872; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Cherry – Cheyney, 1851-1874 (Box 6)
    - Chichester – Child, 1859-1869 (Box 7)
    - Child, David Lee, 1838-1852 (Box 7)
    - Child, Lydia Maria, 1836-1872 (Box 7)
    - Childs – Churen, 1837-1869 (Box 7)
    - Churchill – Clapp (Box 7)
    - Clark, B. – W. (Box 7)
    - Clark, James G. (Box 7)
    - Clark, Myron Holley, 1870 (Box 7)
    - Clarke, A. – W. (Box 7)
    - Clarke, James Freeman (Box 7)
    - Clarkson, Thomas, 1840-1845 (Box 7)
    - Clarkson – Clay (Box 7)
    - Clay, Cassius Marcellus, 1844-1872 (Box 7)
    - Clay, Lucretia Hart (Mrs. Henry), 1831 (Box 7)
    - Cleanland – Clews (Box 7)
    - Clinton – Clubb (Box 7)
    - Coates – Codding (Box 7)
    - Codding, Ichabod, 1862-1863 (Box 7)
    - Codner – Coffin (Box 7)
    - Coffin, Levi, 1861 (Box 7)
    - Coffin, N.W., 1863-1864 (Box 7)
    - Cogswell – Coleman (Box 7)
    - Colfax, Schuyler, 1868-1869 (Box 7)
    - Collar – Colton (Box 7)
    - Combs – Conger (Box 7)
    - Conkling, Alfred, 1867-1373; 51 letters (Box 7)
    - Conkling, Frederick, 1862; 1 letter (Box 7)
    - Conkling, Roscoe, 1864-1874; 13 letters (Box 7)
    - Connell – Cook (Box 7)
    - Cooke – Cooper (Box 8)
    - Copeland – Cornell (Box 8)
    - Cornell, Alonzo B., 1872 (Box 8)
    - Corner – Coye (Box 8)
    - Craig – Crandall (Box 8)
    - Crandall L.S., 1870-1874 (Box 8)
    - Crane – Crawford (Box 8)
    - Crenshaw – Crittenden (Box 8)
    - Crocker – Crooks (Box 8)
    - Cropsey – Crozier (Box 8)
    - Crummell – Cummings (Box 8)
    - Cunningham – Cushing (Box 8)
    - Cushman – Cuyler (Box 8)
    - Dall – Dana (Box 8)
    - Dana, Charles A., 1859-1873 (Box 8)
    - Dana, Federal, 1831-1870; 15 letters (Box 8)
    - Danforth – Davidson (Box 8)
    - Davis, A. – S. (Box 8)
    - Davis, Paulina Wright, 1851-1871 (Box 8)
    - Davis, Thomas T., 1855-1863 (Box 8)
    - Dawes – Dayton (Box 8)
    - Dawson, Mary A., 1849-1874; 4 folders (Box 9)
    - Day – Dayton (Box 9)
    - Dealy – Delavan (Box 9)
    - Delavan, Edward C., 1832-1870; 6 folders (Box 9)
    - Delcoetz – Devine (Box 9)
    - Deuyer, Thomas Ainge, 1856-1874; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Dewey – Deyo (Box 9)
    - Dibbie – Dix (Box 9)
    - Dix, Dorothea, 1857; 1 letter (Box 9)
    - Dixon – Dixwell (Box 9)
    - Doane – Dorrance (Box 9)
    - Dorrance, D.G., 1840-1859; 20 folders (Box 10)
    - Dorrance, D.G., 1860-1876; 4 folders (Box 11)
    - Dorwin – Doty (Box 11)
    - Doubleday, Ammi, 1845-1861; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Dougall – Douglass (Box 11)
    - Douglass, Frederick, 1849-1874; 7 folders (Box 11)
    - Dow – Doxtater (Box 11)
    - Drake – Drummond (Box 11)
    - Dudley – Duer (Box 11)
    - Duffin – Dutton (Box 11)
    - Duval, W.O. (Box 11)
    - Dwight – Dye (Box 11)
    - Earle – Eaton (Box 12)
    - Eaton, George (Box 12)
    - Echols – Edwards (Box 12)
    - Edwards, John B.
      - 1831-1845, 13 folders (Box 12)
      - 1846-1851, 12 folders (Box 13)
      - 1852-1857, 12 folders (Box 14)
      - 1858-1862, 12 folders (Box 15)
      - 1863-1869, 12 folders (Box 16)
      - 1870-1874, 10 folders (Box 17)
    - Edwards, Justin, 1833-1851 (Box 17)
    - Egbert – Eldridge (Box 17)
    - Ellinson – Ely (Box 17)
    - Enos – Etson (Box 17)
    - Evans – Everson (Box 17)
    - Fabrick – Fairbanks (Box 18)
    - Fairchild – Farnsworth (Box 18)
    - Farquhar – Fay (Box 18)
    - Fee, John Gregg, 1850-1874; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Feeser – Fessenden (Box 18)
    - Field – Fillmore (Box 18)
    - Finch – Finney (Box 18)
    - Finney, Charles Grandison, 1839-1855 (Box 18)
    - Fish, William H., 1854-1874 (Box 18)
    - Fish – Fisher (Box 18)
    - Fisk – Fitler (Box 18)
    - Fitzhugh – Fitzsimmons (Box 18)
    - Flack – Flournoy (Box 18)
    - Fogg – Foote (Box 18)
    - Forbes – Foster (Box 18)
    - Foster, Abigail Kelly, 1843-1869 (Box 18)
    - Fourney – Fowler (Box 18)
    - Fowler, Loring, 1839-1873 (Box 18)
    - Fowlkes – Fox (Box 18)
    - Francis – Fraser (Box 18)
    - Frederick – Freeman (Box 18)
    - Fremont, John C., 1861 (Box 18)
    - French – Fritts (Box 18)
    - Frone – Frothingham (Box 18)
    - Frothingham, Octavius Brooks (Box 18)
    - Fry – Fuller, Hannah (Box 18)
    - Fuller, Henry, 1838-1867; 8 folders (Box 19)
    - Fuller, James – Furness, 1839-1874 (Box 19)
    - Gag – Gan, 1827-1874 (Box 19)
    - Gar – Ger, 1837-1874 (Box 19)
    - Gib – Gil, 1824-1868 (Box 19)
    - Gilb – Gill, 1845-1871 (Box 19)
    - Gille – Gla, 1859-1874 (Box 19)
    - Gle – Gol, 1835-1874 (Box 19)
    - Gon – Goo, 1855-1873 (Box 19)
    - Good – Gor, 1855-1870 (Box 19)
    - Gos – Grac, 1835-1873 (Box 19)
    - Grah – Grang, 1821-1872 (Box 20)
    - Grant – Grav, 1826-1874 (Box 20)
    - Gray, A. – Gray, M., 1837-1874 (Box 20)
    - Greely – Green, N., 1845-1871 (Box 20)
    - Green, S. – Grid, 1835-1874 (Box 20)
    - Grif – Groso, 1842-1872 (Box 20)
    - Gross – Gum, 1852-1872 (Box 20)
    - Gantt, Thomas T., 1852-1871 (Box 20)
    - Garnet, Henry Highland, 1836-1873; 13 items (Box 20)
    - Garrison, William Lloyd, 1861-1870; 3 items (Box 20)
    - Gates, Seth M., 1839-1872; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Giddings, Joshua R.
      - to Seth M. Gates, 1842-1848 (Box 20)
      - to Gerrit Smith, 1846-1870; 30 items (Box 20)
    - Gold, Theodore, 1823-1832 (Box 20)
    - Goodel, William, 1831-1872; 36 items (Box 20)
    - Grant, Ulysses Simpson, 1872; 2 items, secretarial (Box 20)
    - Greeley, Horace, 1852-1872; 21 items (Box 20)
    - Green, Beriah
      - 1834-Aug 1838, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Sep 1838-1872, 12 folders (Box 21)
    - Green, Johnathan S., 1857-1860 (Box 21)
    - Griffiths, Julia Crafts, circa 1850-1869; 18 items (Box 21)
    - Grimke, Angelina, See Weld, Angelina Grimke (Box 38)
    - Grimke, Sarah, 1840-1872; 16 items (Box 21)
    - Gurley, Ralph Randolph, 1827-1854; 13 items (Box 21)
    - Had – Haig, 1819-1875 (Box 21)
    - Hain – Hal, 1824-1872 (Box 21)
    - Ham – Han, 1840-1874 (Box 21)
    - Hard – Harris, 1841-1874 (Box 21)
    - Harrison – Harw, 1860-1874 (Box 21)
    - Has – Hat, 1828-1874 (Box 21)
    - Hav – Hawley, F., 1847-1874 (Box 21)
    - Hawley, J. – Hawk, 1847-1870 (Box 22)
    - Hay – Hayn, 1836-1873 (Box 22)
    - Hayt – Haz, 1846-1873 (Box 22)
    - Hea – Hen, 1859-1874 (Box 22)
    - Hep – Hey, 1829-1874 (Box 22)
    - Hib – Hig, 1841-1870 (Box 22)
    - Hil – Hine, 1850-1871 (Box 22)
    - Hink – Hit, 1850-1870 (Box 22)
    - Hoa – Holland, E., 1859-1870 (Box 22)
    - Holland, F. – Holley, Myron, 1839-1870 (Box 22)
    - Holley, O. – Hollo, 1836-1873 (Box 22)
    - Holly – Hon, 1832-1874 (Box 22)
    - Hoo – Hopk, 1831-1870 (Box 22)
    - Hopp – Hou, 1837-1872 (Box 22)
    - How – Hoy, 1837-1870 (Box 22)
    - Hub – Hul, 1837-1871 (Box 22)
    - Hum – Hunt, T., 1835-1873 (Box 22)
    - Hunt, W. – Huntington, 1841-1874 (Box 22)
    - Hur – Hut, 1847-1874 (Box 22A)
    - Hya – Hys, 1845-1874 (Box 22A)
    - Hammond, Charles A., 1858-1874 (Box 22A)
    - Hammond, Jabez Delano, 1836-1854; 2 folders (Box 22A)
    - Hardin, James A., 1865-1874; 2 folders (Box 22A)
    - Helper, Hinton R., 1856-1859; 5 items (Box 22A)
    - Herring, Elbert, 1860-1873 (Box 22A)
    - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1855-1867; 8 items (Box 22A)
    - Holley, Sallie, 1841-1873 (Box 22A)
    - Hosmer, William, 1869-1871 (Box 22A)
    - Howard, Oliver Otis, 1868-1873; 9 items (Box 22A)
    - Howe, Julia Ward, 1869-1874; 7 items (Box 22A)
    - Howe, Samuel Gridley, 1836-1872 (Box 22A)
    - Hull, N.V., 1851-1873 (Box 22A)
    - Huntington, Nehemiah, 1828-1852 (Box 22A)
    - Imb – Ive, 1855-1874 (Box 22A)
    - Jac – Jackson, Job, 1838-1874 (Box 22A)
    - Jackson, James Caleb, 1838-1873 (Box 22A)
    - Jackson, Julia – James, H., 1833-1868 (Box 22A)
    - James, J. – Jaw, 1837-1874 (Box 23)
    - Jay, William, 1836-1857; 24 items (Box 23)
    - Jef – Jewett, 1830-1874 (Box 23)
    - Jenkins, Hiram, 1856-1866 (Box 23)
    - Jenkins, Timothy, 1841-1859; 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Jocelyn, Simeon D., 1834-1872 (Box 23)
    - Joh – Johnson, J., 1828-1874 (Box 23)
    - Johnson, J.R. – Johnston, 1843-1873 (Box 23)
    - Johnson, Oliver, 1839-1873 (Box 23)
    - Jol – Jones, S.W., 1839-1874 (Box 23)
    - Jones, T. – Jones, Wm., 1839-1869 (Box 23)
    - Jones, David S., 1831-1835; 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Jones, David S., 1836-1844; 3 folders (Box 24)
    - Jons – Jul, 1830-1873 (Box 24)
    - Julian, George Washington, 1852-1873 (Box 24)
    - Kak – Kay, 1850-1873 (Box 24)
    - Kea – Kello, 1837-1873 (Box 24)
    - Kellog, H.H., 1839-1872 (Box 24)
    - Keily – Kepp, 1833-1874 (Box 24)
    - Kern – Keyes, 1844-1874 (Box 24)
    - Key, Francis Scott, 1827; 1 item (Box 24)
    - Kief – Kinb, 1856-1873 (Box 24)
    - King – King, F., 1835-1874 (Box 24)
    - King, H. – King, 1840-1874 (Box 24)
    - Kingsley, Victor, 1859-1874 (Box 24)
    - Kingman – Kirk, J., 1834-1873 (Box 24)
    - Kirkland – Kirt, 1825-1871 (Box 24)
    - Kli – Knox, 1831-1844 (Box 24)
    - Knowles – Kyr, 1835-1869 (Box 24)
    - Lad – Lama, 1836-1874 (Box 24)
    - Lamb – Lane, 1868-1872 (Box 24)
    - Lang – Langrand, 1856-1870 (Box 25)
    - Langston – Lansing, 1854-1874 (Box 25)
    - Lap – Lath, 1833-1873 (Box 25)
    - Latr – Law, 1833-1870 (Box 25)
    - Law – Lea, 1851-1873 (Box 25)
    - Leavitt, Joshua
      - [General], 1834-1872 (Box 25)
      - to Seth M. Gates, 1840 (Box 25)
    - Led – Leml, 1837-1874 (Box 25)
    - Leigh, Charles C., 1862-1874 (Box 25)
    - Lemo – Leon, 1848-1869 (Box 25)
    - Leona – Let, 1840-1874 (Box 25)
    - Lew – Lewis, Y., 1831-1873 (Box 25)
    - Lib – Lind, 1834-1873 (Box 25)
    - Line – Lip, 1847-1872 (Box 25)
    - Lis – Liv, 1834-1869 (Box 25)
    - Littlejohn, DeWitt C., 1857-1872; 18 items (Box 25)
    - Lio – Lon, 1838-1874 (Box 25)
    - Loguen, Jermaine, 1849-1870 (Box 25)
    - Loo – Lord, 1829-1874 (Box 25)
    - Lore – Love, J., 1837-1874 (Box 25)
    - Lovejoy – Lox, 1825-1872 (Box 25)
    - Lovejoy, Owen, 1838-1858; 6 items (Box 25)
    - Lud – Lum, 1819-1874 (Box 25)
    - Lundy, Benjamin, 1833-1834; 2 items (Box 26)
    - Lut – Lyo, 1837-1873 (Box 26)
    - MacArt – MacCar, 1832-1873 (Box 26)
    - MacCle – MacDon, 1854-1874 (Box 26)
    - MacE – MacKay, 1830-1872 (Box 26)
    - MacKeo – MacMay, 1835-1865 (Box 26)
    - MacNei – MacRea, 1830-1873 (Box 26)
    - McWhorter, G.H., 1828-1859 (Box 26)
    - McWhorter, J.L. and Mary, 1862-1874 (Box 26)
    - Mab – Mah, 1820-1873 (Box 26)
    - Maddock, Roger, 1834-1861 (Box 26)
    - Maj – Marr, 1831-1874 (Box 26)
    - Mann, Horace, 1853; 2 items (Box 26)
    - Mars – Marsh, S., 1839-1872 (Box 26)
    - Marshall – Mart, 1847-1874 (Box 26)
    - Marshall, Josiah T., 1821-1862; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Marv – Maste, 1836-1874 (Box 26)
    - Mason, John Thompson, 1842-1867 (Box 26)
    - Masti – May, 1821-1871 (Box 27)
    - Matteson, O.B., 1857-1864; 8 items (Box 27)
    - May, Samuel J., 1846-1869; 11 items (Box 27)
    - Mazzini, Giuseppe, 1866; 1 item (Box 27)
    - Mea – Merc, 1835-1871 (Box 27)
    - Mere – Mey, 1854-1874 (Box 27)
    - Mic – Miles, A., 1838-1873 (Box 27)
    - Miles, J. – Miller, T., 1836-1874 (Box 27)
    - Miller, R.B., 1850-1873; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Milli – Mills, R., 1840-1871 (Box 27)
    - Mills, S. – Miz, 1826-1872 (Box 27)
    - Mof – Moo, 1846-1872 (Box 27)
    - Montgomery, Thomas C., 1850-1873; 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Mor – Morgan, G., 1836-1872 (Box 27)
    - Morgan, H. – Morris, H., 1837-1873 (Box 28)
    - Morris, T. – Morti, 1840-1873 (Box 28)
    - Morto – Moy, 1857-1873 (Box 28)
    - Morton, Edwin, 1855-1875; 3 folders (Box 28)
    - Morton, William Thomas G., 1864; 1 item (Box 28)
    - Murp – Murr, 1866-1873 (Box 28)
    - Mud – Munson, 1836-1873 (Box 28)
    - Mus – Mys, 1834-1863 (Box 28)
    - Nad – Nat, 1850-1871 (Box 28)
    - Nea – Nei, 1854-1873 (Box 28)
    - Nel – New, 1830-1874 (Box 28)
    - Neumann, Emma, 1833-1867; 3 items (Box 28)
    - Nic – Nix, 1840-1872 (Box 28)
    - Nob – North, 1843-1874 (Box 28)
    - North, John W., 1849-1874; 21 items (Box 28)
    - Northr – Nortwich, 1833-1873 (Box 28)
    - Nott – Nye, 1840-1873 (Box 28)
    - Noyes, John Humphrey, Helen C. and Victor, 1864-1877; 3 items (Box 28)
    - Oak – Ore, 1840-1873 (Box 29)
    - O'Reilly, Henry, 1842-1873 (Box 29)
    - Orr – Osg, 1837-1874 (Box 29)
    - Oss – Owe, 1825-1874 (Box 29)
    - Owen, Robert Dale, 1863-1864 (Box 29)
    - Pac – Pai, 1836-1869 (Box 29)
    - Pal – Pao, 1835-1871 (Box 29)
    - Par – Parsh, 1839-1872 (Box 29)
    - Parker, Theodore, 1854-1860; 3 letters (Box 29)
    - Parso – Pau, 1836-1873 (Box 29)
    - Pay – Payn, 1854-1872 (Box 29)
    - Peab – Peal, 1839-1874 (Box 29)
    - Peabody, Elizabeth Palmer, 1855-1871; 13 letters (Box 29)
    - Peck – Pei, 1841-1872 (Box 29)
    - Pel – Penno, 1822-1874 (Box 29)
    - Penne – Pep, 1836-1861 (Box 29)
    - Per – Pet, 1826-1874 (Box 29)
    - Phe – Phi, 1839-1873 (Box 29)
    - Phelps, Anos, 1835-1846 (Box 29)
    - Phelps, John Wolcott, (General), 1872-1873; 6 letters (Box 29)
    - Phillips, Wendell, 1851-1867; undated; 15 letters and 1 item non-correspondence (Box 29)
    - Pho – Phoe, 1868-1874 (Box 30)
    - Pia – Pin, 1859-1871 (Box 30)
    - Pierpont, John, 1839-1865; 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Pillsbury, Parker, 1863-1871; 12 letters (Box 30)
    - Pla – Plu, 1833-1871 (Box 30)
    - Plumb, David, 1862-1874; 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Post, George F., 1859-1870 (Box 30)
    - Pog – Poq, 1828-1877 (Box 30)
    - Por – Pos, 1837-1872 (Box 30)
    - Pot – Pott, 1834-1873 (Box 30)
    - Pou – Pow, 1853-1870 (Box 30)
    - Pra – Pre, 1834-1873 (Box 30)
    - Pri – Pro, 1831-1872 (Box 30)
    - Pru – Pry, 1859-1S73 (Box 30)
    - Pur – Pyl, 1852-1874 (Box 30)
    - Qua – Qui, 1850-1869 (Box 30)
    - Quiney, Edmund, 1839-1852 (Box 30)
    - Rad – Randa, 1841-1870 (Box 30)
    - Rand, Asa, 1845-1847; undated; 3 folders (Box 30)
    - Rando – Rans, 1837-1874 (Box 30)
    - Ras – Ray, 1832-1874 (Box 31)
    - Ray, Charles Bennett, 1847-1873; 12 items (Box 31)
    - Rea – Red, 1842-1874 (Box 31)
    - Reeder, David, 1862-1865; 3 folders (Box 31)
    - Ree – Renssalaer, J., 1828-1874 (Box 31)
    - Rensselaer, M. – Rey, 1834-1871 (Box 31)
    - Rensselaer, See also Van Rensselaer surname
    - Rhe – Rice, C., 1852-1874 (Box 31)
    - Rice, D. – Rice, R., 1834-1874 (Box 31)
    - Rich – Rit, 1828-1871 (Box 31)
    - Richards, James (Rev.), 1863-1864; 6 letters (Box 31)
    - Richards, William C., 1868-1874; 9 letters (Box 31)
    - Richmond, B.W., 1856-1860; undated; 8 letters (Box 31)
    - Richter, M.A., 1859-1867; 9 letters (Box 31)
    - Rob – Robertson, 1837-1872 (Box 31)
    - Robie – Roch, 1832-1870 (Box 31)
    - Rock – Rogers, C., 1836-1874 (Box 31)